

LJUPCHO NAUMOV Analyst | MSc | BSc

I am interested in business and financial analyst positions. I have strong technical skills in R & Tableau to create automated reporting and dashboards, as well business and financial experience to quickly deliver actionable insights. I have full working rights in the Netherlands (zoekjaar).



lj.naumov@gmail.com



+389 70 350 270



ODB: 27.01.1995



Ljupcho.com

EDUCATION



Bocconi University

Milan, Italy

MSc in Economics and Management of Innovation and Technology - GPA: 27/30 (103/110)

Sep. 2016 - Dec. 2018

- Coursework: Statistics for Economics and Business, Industry & Competition Analysis
- Thesis: "Indie Makers: Success Factors for Bootstrapped Software Businesses"
- ISU Scholarship: full tuition and housing



WHU-Otto Beisheim School of Management

Master's Exchange Program

• Coursework: Predictive Analytics with R, Financial Modelling with Excel, Financial Statements Analysis (Advanced)

Vallendar, Germany Jan. 2018 - April 2018



Bocconi University

Milan. Italy

BSc in International Economics, Management & Finance, Major in Finance - GPA: 27.4/30 (103/110)

Sep. 2013 - Sep. 2016

- Thesis: "The Principal-Agent Problem in Actively Managed Mutual Funds"
- Bocconi & ISU Scholarship: full tuition and housing

WORK EXPERIENCE



Moi Doktori (moidoktori.mk)

Co-founder, Product, Marketing, Sales

Skopje, N. Macedonia March 2019 - Present

- Launched a doctor booking platform in North Macedonia that scaled to 2500+ active users.
- Promoted the platform on 3 national TV morning shows (1st, 3rd and 6th largest TV station).
- Went viral on twitter by connecting with local influencers, top tweet of the week in Macedonia.



RZ Ekonomika, public financial services and metallurgy parts trading company.

Business Analyst

Skopje, N. Macedonia Aug. 2018 - Present

- Replaced a senior employee in bookkeeping for a warehouse with 70k parts.
- Assisted in responding to a hostile takeover attempt.



Simple360.io

Co-founder, Product, Marketing, Sales

Milan, Italy

Oct. 2017 - May 2018

- Launched a team feedback software based on hedge fund manager Ray Dalio's internal tools.
- Accepted in 2018s batch of AppWorks, Taiwan's leading startup accelerator.
- Conducted 15 lead user interviews to identify pain points and define product strategy.
- Project acquired by a Texas based company.

Xandas New Media Ventures, angel fund focused on building ventures internally. Business Analyst, Product Manager

Milan, Italy

April 2017 - Sep. 2017

- Collaborated directly with serial entrepreneurs Fabio Pezzotti (\$30M in exits) and Guillaume Alabert (\$58M) on Sharado.com, a platform for sharing economy jobs.
- Evaluated incoming business plans and funding requests from Italian entrepreneurs.
- Analyzed blue-collar job market by competitor analysis to establish product strategy and features.
- Managed daily communication with remote developers to ensure timely delivery of quality product.

Sparkasse Bank, commercial bank with HQ in Graz, Austria, part of Erste Group. Intern

Skopje, N. Macedonia June 2014 - Aug. 2014

- Rotated across Risk Management, Corporate Loan Management, and Central Branch.
- Analyzed financial statements for solvency and liquidity indicators

LANGUAGE SKILLS

Macedonian – Native | English – C2 | Italian, Serbian, Bulgarian – B2 | Spanish – B1

DATA & IT SKILLS

R – Full capability to load, transform and visualize data through code, and distribute analysis in reports & dashboards. Proficiency in various packages including Tidyverse and shinydashboard. Projects: Ljupcho.com/R

Excel – Proficient, ECDL certified. Built leveraged buyout financial models from scratch, applied SaaS valuation models.

SQL, Tableau, PowerBI – Completed SQLZOO and the official Tableau Training videos.

HTML, CSS, JavaScript – working knowledge. Projects: github.com/ljupch0